Savannah Hammerton

PHD STUDENT, EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS

University of Georgia College of Public Health

□ 423 544 2453 | 💌 savannah.hammerton@uga.edu | 🏕 smhammerton.com | 🕡 smhammerton | 🛅 smhammerton

About

Graduate student working towards PhD in Epidemiology & Biostatistics (concentration in Data Analysis and Modeling). Particular interest and research emphasis in infectious diseases, correlates of protection for viral vaccine development, infectious disease dynamics, and modeling. Past experience in healthcare, providing strong contextual understanding of disease determinants, prevention, treatment, and outcomes, as well as an understanding of the real world implications of public health research and practice on individuals. This experience also drives context-aware data analytic approaches to answering epidemiological questions. Passionate and driven to build a career that benefits others.

Education

University of Georgia Athens, GA

PHD EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS (DATA ANALYSIS & MODELING EMPHASIS)

2022-Present

University of Georgia Athens, GA

MS EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS (EPIDEMIOLOGY EMPHASIS) | CERTIFICATE IN INFECTIOUS DISEASE EPIDEMIOLOGY

Columbus State University Columbus, GA

BS, Health Science 2018-2020

Chattanooga College Chattanooga, TN

DIPLOMA, PRACTICAL NURSING 2014-2015

Relevant Experience

University of Georgia, Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics

Athens, GA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISANT

2022-Present

- Assist Dr. Andreas Handel in research for the Center for Influenza Vaccine Research for High-Risk Populations (CIVR-HRP) grant at the University of Georgia. Aid in research and data analysis on influenza vaccines, particularly data related to improved seasonal and universal influenza vaccine development.
- Perform secondary data analysis research on influenza antibodies as correlates of protection and apply protection probability curves to vaccine immunogenicity data to assess and compare vaccine efficacy.
- Perform secondary data analysis research on norovirus antibodies as correlates of protection to support vaccine research and development.
- Use bayesian modeling approaches to answer complex research questions with human clinical trial data.

Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Center on Birth Defects and Developmental Disabilities

Atlanta, GA

RESEARCH EPIDEMIOLOGIST, PUBLIC HEALTH DATA MANAGEMENT AND ANALYSIS ORISE FELLOW

2022-Present

- Support the MAT-LINK (MATernaL and Infant Network to Understand Outcomes Associated with Medication for Opioid Use Disorder during Pregnancy) team as SWEP (Student Worksite Experience Program) volunteer July 2022-Juli 2023 and ORISE Fellow July-September 2023.
- · Conduct data cleaning, analysis, and management using statistical software (e.g. R, SAS, etc.), and interpretation.
- Assist team with data quality assurance checks and other reviews of data. Conduct literature reviews related to opioid use disorder, pregnancy, infectious diseases, and other topics.
- Develop instructional material on use of R and RMarkdown for reports and publications.
- Support the development of statistical briefs, standard operating procedures, and publically available code for outcome identification using ICD-9 and ICD-10 codes.
- Perform primary and secondary analyses for conference presentation and manuscript development.

University of Georgia, Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics

Athens, GA

GRADUATE DEPARTMENTAL ASSISANT

- Assist in administrative departmental tasks, faculty retreats/meeting planning, and department event planning. Create and maintain spreadsheets on department classes, students, etc. Develop presentation materials and assist in orientation. Generate documents with information on degree programs, Graduate School processes, etc.
- · Conduct research with Dr. Jose Cordero, planning and implementing a systematic review of environmental exposures and preterm birth.

Georgetown Behavioral Health Institute

Georgetown, TX

LICENSED VOCATIONAL NURSE 2016-2016

• LVN working on adolescent male and female units, military unit. Conducted medication administration, milieu management, conflict resolution, patient chart management. Responsible for verbal de-escalation of agitated patients, medical complication and event management. Aided in coordination of care between all health care providers.

Encompass Home Health Pediatrics

Temple, TX

LICENSED VOCATIONAL NURSE

2016-2016

• Provided pediatric patient care for those needing 24-hour care or on hospice. Responsible for nutrition, hygiene, infection control, medication administration, respiratory status maintenance. Provided support to families of patients and socialization to patients throughout shifts.

Research

Examining antibodies as correlates of protection against norovirus clinical outcomes

University of Georgia

MS THESIS PROJECT, ADVISOR - DR. ANDREAS HANDEL

2021-Present

Comparing standard- and high-dose influenza vaccine efficacy using immunogenicity data

University of Georgia

PRIMARY RESEARCHER 2023-Present

Presentations

Comparing standard- and high-dose Fluzone vaccine efficacy across seasons and strains

University of Georgia

CIVICS ANNUAL MEETING

2022

• Oral presentation on use of HAI-protection curve to predict influenza vaccine effectiveness (VE) using immunogenicity data in the absence of infection outcomes and comparing theoretical VEs of standard- and high-dose influenza vaccination.

HIV Tests and Diagnoses During Pregnancy Among People with Opioid Use Disorder

ORISE (CDC)

IDSOG Annual Meeting

2023

• Poster presenting results on associations between prenatal care and medication for opioid use disorder and HIV testing, positivity, and control in pregnancy people with HIV.

Honors and Awards

Scholarship, Travel Stipend

University of Washington

SUMMER INSTITUTE IN STATISTICS AND MODELING IN INFECTIOUS DISEASES (SISMID)

Summa cum laude

Chattanooga College

DIPLOMA, PRACTICAL NURSING

2015

Director's Award for Consistent Academic and Clinical Excellence

Chattanooga College

DIPLOMA, PRACTICAL NURSING

2015

Certifications and Professional Training

Assurances of Confidentiality

CENTERS FOR DISEASE CONTROL AND PREVENTION

2022

Social and Behavioral Research

CITI PROGRAM

2021

Essentials of Public Health Research

CITI PROGRAM

2019

Research Involving Human Subjects

CITI PROGRAM

2019



Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics Case-Control Studies Class

University of Georgia

LIGHTNING TALK JUDGE

April 2023

• Judged final project lightning talks of case-control studies for required graduate course on case-control study design, implementation, and analysis along with course instructor and one oher additional judge. Presentations were judged based on poster design, content, accurate discussion of study, sufficient question answers, and presentation timeliness and quality.

College of Public Health Curriculum Committee

University of Georgia

STUDENT REPRESENTATIVE

2022-202

· Review, inform changes, and vote on new College of Public Health degrees, certificates, and classes.

Athens Water Festival

Athens, GA

VOLUNTEER

September 2022

• Aided in setup and breakdown of annual Athens Water Festival. Collaborated with other volunteers to engage and educate children on marine life, Georgia biodiversity, and geology.

Graduate Scholars of Epidemiology & Biostatistics (GSEB)

University of Georgia

SECRETARY

2021-2022

• Managed fundraising events and community food pantry. Planned and recorded regular executive board and general body meetings. Developed and led events open to department and college students. Maintained communication with department members to assess student needs and announce organization events. Maintained records for future executive board members.

Skills

Data Analysis

PRIMARY CODING LANGUAGE: R | ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE IN: SAS, STATA, SPSS

Literature Searches and Management

ENDNOTE, ENDNOTE CLICK, ZOTERO

Laboratory Biosafety Level 2 Practices

EXPERIENCE IN SAFE MICROBIOLOGY LABORATORY PRACTICES WHEN WORKING WITH HUMAN PATHOGENS

Infectious Disease Modeling

UNDERSTANDING OF INFECTIOUS DISEASE MODELING CONCEPTS, AND EXPERIENCE IN FITTING INFECTIOUS DISEASE MODELS

Organization

SKILLED IN MANAGING MULTIPLE TASKS AND PROJECTS, MAINTAINING HIGH QUALITY OF WORK

Communication

EXPERIENCE IN CLINICAL, RESEARCH, AND PRIVATE GROUPS REQUIRING LARGE AMOUNTS OF COLLABORATION

Health Education

HAVE PROVIDED HEALTH EDUCATION IN BOTH CLINICAL AND NON-CLINICAL SETTINGS

Leadership/Management

EXPERIENCE IN MANAGEMENT, LEADERSHIP OF MULTIPLE EMPLOYEES

Organizations_

Graduate Scholars of Epidemiology & Biostatistics (GSEB)

University of Georgia

2021-Present

Center for the Ecology of Infectious Diseases (CEID)

University of Georgia

2021-Present

Eta Sigma Gamma (ESG) | Health Science Honor Society

University of Columbus

2019-2020